<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Choosing an Installation Option on Wallaroo</title>
    <link>https://docs.wallaroolabs.com/python-installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Choosing an Installation Option on Wallaroo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.wallaroolabs.com/python-installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing with Docker</title>
      <link>https://docs.wallaroolabs.com/python-installation/python-docker-installation-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.wallaroolabs.com/python-installation/python-docker-installation-guide/</guid>
      <description>To get you up and running quickly with Wallaroo, we have provided a Docker image which includes Wallaroo and related tools needed to run and modify a few example applications. We should warn that this Docker image was created with the intent of getting users started quickly with Wallaroo and is not intended to be a fully customizable development environment or suitable for production.
Installing Docker MacOS There are instructions for getting Docker up and running on MacOS on the Docker website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing with Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://docs.wallaroolabs.com/python-installation/python-vagrant-installation-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.wallaroolabs.com/python-installation/python-vagrant-installation-guide/</guid>
      <description>To get you up and running quickly with Wallaroo, we have provided a Vagrantfile which includes Wallaroo and related tools needed to run and modify a few example applications. We should warn that this Vagrantfile was created with the intent of getting users started quickly with Wallaroo and is not intended to be suitable for production. Wallaroo in Vagrant runs on Ubuntu Linux Xenial.
Set up Environment for the Wallaroo Tutorial Linux and MacOS If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already done so, create a directory called ~/wallaroo-tutorial and navigate there by running:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing with Wallaroo Up</title>
      <link>https://docs.wallaroolabs.com/python-installation/python-wallaroo-up-installation-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.wallaroolabs.com/python-installation/python-wallaroo-up-installation-guide/</guid>
      <description>Supported Systems Wallaroo Up has been tested on:
 Amazon Linux 2 CentOS 7 Debian  Buster (Testing) Jessie Stretch  Fedora  27 28  Oracle Linux 7 Ubuntu  Artful Bionic Trusty Xenial   It should also work on Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.
Memory requirements In order to compile the Wallaroo example applications, your system will need to have approximately 3 GB working memory (this can be RAM or swap).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>